Aneeliz Alamo

Human Resources Manager - JcPenney

Murphy, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Aneeliz-Alamo/4145fe60927498ab

Charismatic and driven Human Resources professional with 8 years of experience in Human Resources and Recruiting. Industry experience include Retail, Health & Fitness, Information Technology, and Finance. Goal oriented team player with strong leadership ability, positive attitude, and consistent in meeting and exceeding company goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Human Resources Manager

JcPenney - 2012 to Present

Serve as corporate HR contact for regional, multi-unit field organization of 200 stores and 15 districts

- Implement and drive the human resources strategic initiatives of the company
- Works as a business partner to various lines of business to provide effective customer service and excellent customer relationships, ensuring optimal value of HR to departments at all times including workforce planning and succession planning, skills assessment, building leadership capability, performance management and coaching, team building and change management.
- Provide ongoing support to the leadership team on HR related matters, policies and procedures.
- Provide compensation and benefits support including salary planning, approval of salary actions, promotions and job evaluations, benefits benchmarking and policy communication.
- Planning and preparing the roll out of corporate programs to ensure business needs and corporate timelines are met (e.g. engagement surveys, talent/succession planning, annual performance reviews).
- Partner with managers to retain, develop and motivate people to achieve their fullest potential.
- Coaching, mentoring and influencing the management teams to drive employee engagement and cultural change through constructive leadership behavior.
- Monitor Team Member Relations issues, conducted investigations, and recommended corrective action as appropriate
- · Coordinate with senior management to identify, create, and implement talent management initiatives
- Forecast human capital needs via metric driven research and analysis for 600+ management associates
- Manage performance development plans of management associates
- Act as liaison between business and recruiting partners to identify and select top talent
- · Provide consult in areas of benefits, performance management, labor management, compliance
- Counsel associates at all levels including senior leadership
- Manage the administration of policies and procedures to ensure compliance with local, state, and federal regulations
- Conducted market visits to build associate awareness and promote internal engagement
- Administer and work with business partners on unemployment claims, FMLA or different leaves of absences, EEOC claims, job accommodations, and worker's compensation claims

Area Human Resources Manager

24 Hour Fitness - 2010 to 2012

Compliance/Investigations/Employee Relations

- Counsel management team regarding compliance with all Federal, State, and local employment laws, and acts as company representative in resolving any agency complaints related to such compliance issues.
- Communicate and interpret various Company policies, procedures, laws, standards, and government regulations for team members and managers.
- Conduct and document investigations pertaining to Department of Labor, unemployment, harassment and discrimination complaints in accordance with company guidelines as well as directives by company Legal department.
- Provide advice and counsel to team members, managers and regional leadership on employee relation concerns and ensure all issues are resolved ethically and within company policies and legal guidelines. Provide advice and counsel to district level management in all areas of HR.
- Coach managers and supervisors through coaching process, discipline/corrective action procedures, and labor law compliance.

Talent Management / People Planning /Organization Development raining &Development

- Work closely with district and club level leaders to help create, implement and manage the people strategies to align with business objectives.
- Co-lead the talent management/succession planning process for the district(s) to assist in building capability, managing poor performance, and making sound decisions in regards to team member based actions and sourcing external talent need when applicable.
- Develop, monitor, and educate district and club leadership on staffing methodology, sourcing tactics and selection process.
- Facilitate and/or oversee training on new company programs and HR trainings and other initiatives as needed.
- Develop and implement management practices to ensure organization effectiveness, clear communication, sound employee relations and training and development of team members.
- Participate in the selection process for club level managers.

Strategic partnership with business

- Build relationship with District Managers, Managers in club so seen as "go to" person on people planning.
- Provide counsel, feedback and coaching on broad ranging issues including business operations, process, and all people related actions. Provide forward-looking counsel, coaching and creative solutions that enhance individual and organizational performance.
- Participate in business leadership meetings as a strategic partner to identify human resource implications (team member development, employee relations, talent management, performance management and diversity initiatives) relative to business strategies. Visit club locations on a regular basis with field leadership and with HR team members, provide guidance and coaching to club leaders on all HR related and people related activities.
- Ensure compliance with Leave of Absence documents, I-9 documents, unemployment claims, worker's compensation claims.

Management of Human Resources Function

- Supervise and coordinate rollouts and ongoing implementation of company programs in the areas of Employee Relations, Staffing, Compensation, Benefits, Training & Development. Manage or oversee the management of various HR projects/initiatives for region. Provide leadership, act as mentor.
- Respond to employment related requests. Provide counsel through the interpretation of policies and programs, and guidance and coaching in areas of discipline, payroll, benefits and other employee relation

areas. Escalate recommendations to sr. mgmt. as necessary. Ensure the administration of on-going employee processes within the region (e.g. performance management, compensation review, benefit enrollment etc) when required..

National Recruiting Administrator

24 Hour Fitness - 2009 to 2010

Recruiting support for front line positions for all nationwide 24 Hour Fitness clubs

- Partner with 43 District Managers nationwide to coordinate front line needs and job fairs
- Responsible for all highly confidential criminal background check issues for candidates that are on pending hired status
- Designated to re-launch the College Recruiting Program for Personal Trainers
- o Successfully established contacts for schools in each region of the company all over the United States
- o Directly helped enrich the Personal Training candidate pipeline through these efforts
- Business Systems Administrator for the company's Applicant Tracking System (ATS)
- o Assist Team Members and candidates in troubleshooting technical issues with the system
- o Worked with the IT team and maintained an average of same day response time to most tickets
- Project Leader for the ATS migration of the company from SeleXpert to Kenexa
- o Designated Business Systems Administrator for Kenexa upon rollout of the new system
- o Project Manager for 2 critical work streams for the migration that will affect candidate applicant flow
- * Responsible for creating and managing all the forms associated with our online application system for both external and internal candidates
- * Responsible for critically reviewing the company's current and past processes in the candidate application flow and making recommendations to streamline and automate manual processes
- o Involvement in quality assurance and critical testing of the product before go live
- Full cycle recruiting support for Corporate and Field Management positions
- o Assisted the team on full cycle requisitions

Manager of Recruiting

Rightstaff Inc - Dallas, TX - 2007 to 2009

Full cycle sourcing, recruiting, and placement of IT professionals for project based assignments and direct hire positions. Specialize in infrastructure and development positions with a strong focus in recruiting for a myriad of development technologies (C#, VB.net, ASP.net, Java, SQL)

- Expert in sourcing candidates and performing Boolean searches in various job boards
- Utilized internal web-based Applicant Tracking System (Bullhorn) to retain a database of candidates with different skill sets
- Negotiate pricing, contracts, salaries, hourly rates, benefits, completion bonuses with candidates
- Conduct phone screens, interviews, reference checks, and other pre-employment processes for candidates and clients
- Establish strong rapport with candidates by performing weekly quality check calls to consultants on billing and consistent follow up calls to candidates, ensuring the highest quality of service to both candidates and clients
- Manage and mentor a team of senior recruiters
- o Conduct weekly metrics meetings and administer the team's metrics reports
- o Work closely with the IT Practice Director in generating additional revenue for the company
- Excel in a fast paced environment, consistently hitting 115% of projected goals as directed by management
- Consistent in producing \$30,000 \$60,000 in Gross Margin per month for the company, including direct hire placements for hard to find positions resulting in overall client satisfaction
- Worked with Vendor Management Systems for different clients (Taleo, Chimes, ZeroChaos, etc.)
- Work with third party companies and administer corp to corp or 1099 paperwork for contractors
- Administer and assist clients with H1 and visa processing

• Recruiter of the Month for Q2 and Q3 of 2008

Account Executive

Robert Half Technology - Dallas, TX - 2007 to 2007

Full cycle sourcing, recruiting, and placement of IT professionals for project based assignments and direct hire positions. Specialized in infrastructure and development positions with a strong focus in recruiting for a myriad of development technologies (C#, VB.net, ASP.net, Java, SQL)

- Expert in sourcing candidates and performing Boolean searches in various job boards
- Utilized internal Applicant Tracking System (MicroJ) to retain a database of candidates with different skill sets
- Regularly attended user group meetings and job fairs for networking and recruitment efforts
- · Negotiated pricing, contracts, salaries, hourly rates, benefits, completion bonuses with candidates
- Conducted phone screens, interviews, reference checks, and other pre-employment processes for candidates and clients
- Established strong rapport with candidates by performing weekly quality check calls to consultants on billing and consistent follow up calls to candidates, ensuring the highest quality of service to both candidates and clients
- Excelled in a fast paced environment, consistently hitting 115% of projected goals as directed by management
- Consistent in producing \$20,000 \$25,000 in Gross Margin per month for the company with an average of 15 20 consultants on billing
- Worked with Vendor Management Systems (Taleo, Chimes)
- Consistently met and exceeded 125 candidate contacts per week goal
- Consistently met and exceeded 15 in-person interviews per week goal

Corporate Recruiter/Human Resources Administrator

US-Analytics Solutions Group, LLC - Dallas, TX - 2005 to 2007

Full cycle recruiting for active, open positions with the firm for both internal positions and permanent/contract positions for clients. Specialized in Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing positions, particularly in Hyperion, Cognos, and Oracle (both technical and functional). Also specialized in recruiting for Symantec and Veritas products

- Utilized internal Applicant Tracking System (Recruiting Solutions) to retain a database of candidates with different skill sets
- Recruited and staffed 60% of the company's internal employees with positions varying from marketing, sales, and IT consultants and sub contractors
- Worked closely with the Account Managers to achieve and exceed company goal, with 200% growth in 2006 in the Specialized Placement Services division
- Regularly attended user group meetings for networking and branding
- Negotiated pricing, contracts, salaries, benefits, and bonuses with candidates and potential internal employees
- · Maintained active candidate database and open opportunities utilizing an internet based recruiting system
- Worked with hiring managers to create job descriptions and performing job analysis to maintain accurate job descriptions and appropriate compensations
- Processed background and reference checks for potential employees or candidates
- · Managed and trained new recruiters
- Managed the termination process and administration for internal employees
- Managed 3rd party relationships to help expedite the internal recruitment process
- Employee performance review coordination and salary change administration
- Administered training and certification for internal consultants
- Managed employee relations and legal compliance

- Managed vendor relationships with different accounts
- Subcontractor relationships and administering of legal paperwork for subcontractors
- Liaison for H1 employees and lawyers in dealing with visa and immigration paperwork

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

University of Texas at Dallas - Richardson, TX

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/aneelizalamo